<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
  <records>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Gallo, Michela
          </author>
          <author>
            Moreschi, Luca
          </author>
          <author>
            Del Borghi, Adriana
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>A CRITICAL ENVIRONMENTAL ANALYSIS OF STRATEGIC MATERIALS TOWARDS ENERGY TRANSITION</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>20</volume>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.31025&#x2F;2611-4135&#x2F;2022.15223</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Global consumption of materials is rising rapidly leading to an increase in environmental impacts associated with the supply chain. Similar issues also affect a set of materials strategic for the transition towards a sustainable energy production and distribution system: i.e. materials employed in renewable energy (wind turbines and photovoltaic panels), energy storage, electrolysers, electricity distribution networks and electric vehicle charging infrastructure. The analysis identifies, maps and de-fines a priority hierarchy for the environmental risks generated along the life-cycle of strategic raw materials. Standard construction material such as iron, steel and concrete showed the lowest environmental risks whereas platinum and iridium presented by far the highest impacts (respectively about 24.100 and 14.700 kg CO2 eq, 354.000 and 216.000 MJ, and 140 and 83 m3 of water for 1 kg of raw material). Recycled materials have shown to enable the lowering of the environmental risk associated with some raw material production processes (i.e. copper, lead, aluminium, nickel, manganese), whereas specific materials (i.e. platinum, iridium, indium, dysprosium) and related applications will need to be monitored to guarantee a sustainable transition towards renewable energies.</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Detritus</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="generic"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Gahlot, Rohit
          </author>
          <author>
            Mir, Shaila
          </author>
          <author>
            Dhawan, Nikhil
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Recycling of Discarded Photovoltaic Solar Modules for Metal Recovery: A Review and Outlook for the Future</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>36</volume>
      <issue>24</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1021&#x2F;acs.energyfuels.2c02847</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>The extensive deployment of photovoltaic (PV) modules at an expeditious rate worldwide leads to a massive generation of solar waste (60-78 million tonnes by 2050). A stringent recycling effort to recover metal resources from end-of-life PVs is required for resource recovery, circular economy, and subsequent reduction of environmental impact. The recovery of metallic resources (silicon, silver, copper, lead, and tin) from the first-generation PVs and critical elements (tellurium, indium, selenium, and gallium) from second-generation PVs are mainly targeted. This review systematically discusses the recycling literature of both generations of solar cells, market value calculations, recycling preferences, global trends, and the Indian perspective. The status of PV module recycling on a commercial scale and academic research efforts are discussed. The review systematically discusses the various possible pretreatments and extraction&#x2F;refining processes. The pretreatments (physical, chemical, thermal, and hybrid processes) play a decisive role in up-gradation, impurity removal, and metal recovery. The challenges include homogeneous collection, process efficiency, holistic resource recovery, and energy considerations. Toxicity characteristics of both generations, life cycle assessment studies, recycling challenges with proposed flowsheets, and a detailed future outlook are propounded to develop a holistic metal recovery approach. In comparison, crystalline Si PVs comprise the maximum economic value. One tonne of mixed PVs (first and second generation) can yield 9.32 kg of Cu, 0.30 kg of Ag, 33.48 kg of Si, 1.12 kg of Sn, 1.12 kg of Pb, 4.9 g of Cd, 2.5 g of Te, and 3.4 g of In.</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Energy and Fuels</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Dhawan, Nikhil
          </author>
          <author>
            Agrawal, Shrey
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Recycling of discarded photovoltaic solar modules for metal recovery</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>39</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1007&#x2F;s42461-022-00699-6</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>India’s most extensive renewable energy expansion program targets 280 GW of solar energy by 2030. Due to the massive generation of photovoltaic waste (expected 34,600 T by 2030), stringent recycling effort to recover metal resources from end-of-life PVs is required for resource recovery, circular economy, and subsequent reduction in the environmental impact. The present study investigates the recycling potential of end-of-life silicon solar modules. The feed characterization reveals that most of the values in PV modules are concentrated in the frame (pure Al), Si wafer (72–84% Si, 9–12% Al, and 0.13–0.71% Ag), and electrical connections (Cu wire coated with Sn). The Si and Ag values in the feed were beneficiated using water fluidization, and concentrate with 90% Si and 2% Ag was attained in the underflow concentrate. Ag values were recovered in the form of AgCl by leaching in nitric acid and precipitation. After the purification step, the residue containing 99% Si can be further utilized to fabricate Si wafer and Al-Si alloy. The preliminary cost estimations suggest that the proposed process is economically viable for the recycling of solar panels with the maximum value generated from the AgCl precipitate followed by Al panels and Si wafers.</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Mining, Metallurgy and Exploration</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Khalifa, Sherif A.
          </author>
          <author>
            Mastrorocco, Benjamin V.
          </author>
          <author>
            Au, Dylan D.
          </author>
          <author>
            Ovaitt, Silvana
          </author>
          <author>
            Barnes, Teresa M.
          </author>
          <author>
            Carpenter, Alberta C.
          </author>
          <author>
            Baxter, Jason B.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Dynamic material flow analysis of silicon photovoltaic modules to support a circular economy transition</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>30</volume>
      <issue>7</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1002&#x2F;pip.3554</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Solar photovoltaics (PV) are the fastest growing renewable energy technologies for clean, cheap, and sustainable electricity generation. To prepare for rapid scale-up, the PV industry needs to project material requirements to build out all aspects of the supply chain appropriately and plan to handle large volumes of module waste. Impacts of deploying different material circularity strategies to reduce waste and conserve primary resources need to be quantified to inform sustainable material management. Here, we introduce the photovoltaic dynamic material flow analysis (PV DMFA) model based on PV electricity generation. The model quantifies material flows and stocks in the cradle-to-cradle life cycles of utility-scale c-Si PV systems in the United States through 2100. We present case studies for solar flat glass and aluminum frame materials under various scenarios to project the impacts of PV performance, reliability, and processing parameters, material circularity strategies, and module design shifts. In the absence of circularity measures, ~100 million MT of flat glass and ~12 million MT of aluminum would be needed for PV installations by 2100 to meet projected growth in domestic utility PV demand to nearly 1000 TWh in 2100. With optimistic but feasible improvements in efficiency, reliability, and circularity, material intensity and waste could be reduced by nearly 50%. Efficient module collection, minimally intrusive recycling, and careful scrap handling and cleaning could improve material circularity in the PV value chain. This model serves as a sustainability data support tool that may aid in the circular economy transition for PV systems.</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Progress in Photovoltaics: Research and Applications</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Contreras Lisperguer, Rubén
          </author>
          <author>
            Muñoz Cerón, Emilio
          </author>
          <author>
            de la Casa Higueras, Juan
          </author>
          <author>
            Martín, Ricardo Díaz
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Environmental Impact Assessment of crystalline solar photovoltaic panels’ End-of-Life phase: Open and Closed-Loop Material Flow scenarios</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2020</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>23</volume>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1016&#x2F;j.spc.2020.05.008</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>The full life cycle of today&#39;s crystalline photovoltaic (PV) panel is dominated by a linear, open material flow paradigm. The Cradle-to-Cradle philosophy (C2C) applied in a Closed-Loop-Material-Cycle (CLMC) scenario seems promising to move towards a Circular Economy (CE). Environmental impacts associated with the End-of-life (EoL) phase of PV panels, particularly a CLMC scenario, have not yet been evaluated. To this end, this article uses the Life Cycle Assessment methodology to compare a linear Open-Loop-Material-System (OLMS) scenario with a novel CLMC system. Based on our results, the environmental impacts of a PV CLMC scenario are then compared with a Cadmium telluride (CdTe) panel CLMC scenario. In terms of environmental impacts, the recovery of PV materials in a CLMC scenario results in substantial improvements over an OLMS scenario. Closing the material flow has reduced the Climate Change impact factor (kg CO2 eq) by 74%, compared with the OLMS scenario. However, EoL PV recycling technology still remains behind in environmental and energy intensity terms when compared to the EoL CdTe panel recycling technology within a CLMC scenario. Furthermore, during the recycling processes, our results showed that the highest specific energy uptake was 3264 TJ for PV, while for CdTe it was 2748 TJ. On the other hand, the use of toxic chemicals to recover Si and Cd are shown to significantly contribute to the environmental impacts of both EoL PV and CdTe CLMC scenarios. Results show that the CLMC based on C2C principles has a favorable impact by reducing the environmental burden at the EoL. Nevertheless, it is imperative to reduce environmental burdens from the current thermochemical processes used to recycle silicon and to start considering the key role of C2C principles for PV panel design and recycling processes, aiming at the introduction of a CLMC system based on new standards and consistent regulations in order to reduce the environmental impacts of current PV panels, if a sustainable PV technology is desired.</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Sustainable Production and Consumption</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="generic"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Sultana, Irin
          </author>
          <author>
            Chen, Ying
          </author>
          <author>
            Huang, Shaoming
          </author>
          <author>
            Rahman, Md Mokhlesur
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Recycled value-added circular energy materials for new battery application: Recycling strategies, challenges, and sustainability-a comprehensive review</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2022</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>10</volume>
      <issue>6</issue>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.1016&#x2F;j.jece.2022.108728</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>Lithium-ion battery is the key technology to power electronic devices, digital tools, and electric vehicles. As battery-operated technologies are expanding enormously fast, battery raw materials are critical in terms of supply and demand. It is anticipated that battery raw materials preserved in the ores could face a supply crunch in the future. To minimize the future impact, alternative sources of battery raw materials are necessary. Although batteries, photovoltaic and glass sectors contribute to the world economy significantly, they could generate huge amount of underutilised materials at the end-of-life which are often disposed of as wastes or used in low value processes with significant negative economic and environmental impacts. All these wastes contain many high value battery materials, which can be extracted and processed for re-use again and again as economically viable effective raw materials for new battery application in a circular way. Currently, an organized comprehensive review focuses on circular energy materials recovered from waste resources is hardly found. This review takes this opportunity and provides an effective overview on the recovery of circular energy materials from waste resources. Various recycling approaches and challenges of valuable materials recovery from the wastes of lithium-ion battery, photovoltaic, and glass, subsequent purification and nano structuring processes, fabrication of new battery electrodes, and their further application in lithium-ion batteries are thoroughly discussed. This review also provides outlook and considers scientific, economic, environment, and social benefits of the materials recovered from wastes and re-use them in lithium-ion battery technology, and how this affects circular economy.</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Salazar-Peralta, Araceli
          </author>
          <author>
            Pichardo-S, ALfredo
          </author>
          <author>
            Pichardo-S, Ulises
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>La energía solar, una alternativa para la generación de energía renovable</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2016</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>2</volume>
      <issue>511</issue>
      <abstract>Resumen El uso indiscriminado de combustibles fósiles, así como los procesos industriales usados para producir energía eléctrica, ha colaborado al calentamiento global, por la emisión de CO 2. Actualmente, la utilización de la energía solar, ha suscitado la atención de especialistas en diferentes disciplinas científicas, para buscar otras fuentes de energía. Este estudio consiste en la investigación del estatus que guarda el uso de la energía solar para la generación de energía renovable, así como los elementos básicos utilizados en la construcción de un panel solar. Los resultados obtenidos para la generación de energía eléctrica por medio del uso de paneles solares en el año 2012 fue la siguiente: Corea del Sur 655 MW China superó a Alemania con 43000 MW. Se concluye que el uso de energía solar en el suministro de energía eléctrica es una alternativa para reducir en un 60% el consumo de energía eléctrica obtenida de materiales fósiles. Abstract The indiscriminate use of fossil fuels and industrial processes used to produce electricity, has contributed to global warming by CO 2 emissions. Currently, the use of solar energy, has attracted the attention of specialists in different scientific disciplines, to seek other sources of energy. This study involves research status keeping the use of solar energy for the generation of renewable energy as well as the basic elements used in the construction of a solar panel. The results obtained for the generation of electrical energy through the use of solar panels in 2012 was as follows: South Korea 655 MW (MegaWatt),</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Revista de Investigacón y Desarrollo</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Book"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Jutglar
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Generación de energia solar fotovoltaica</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2015</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>7</volume>
      <issue>1</issue>
      <abstract>This article aims to break new ground in academia by bridging the existing knowledge and practice gap on governance during conflict. It seeks to understand the governance dynamics during conflict in the non-government-controlled parts of Syria. It pays particular attention to civil society and state building processes. In doing so, the study spans historical and geographical width. Historically, to understand the roots of the conflict, it assesses the state-civil society-market dynamics of governance in Syria prior to 2011. Nevertheless, its focus is on contemporary Syria between March, 2011 and May, 2014. Geographically, its particular attention and in-depth analysis is on three areas in the non-government-controlled parts: Al-Raqqa (the city), Deir Ez-zor (Al-Mayadeen and the city) and Aleppo (the city).</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Syria Studies</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Plá, Juan
          </author>
          <author>
            Bolzi, Claudio
          </author>
          <author>
            Durán, Julio César
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Energía solar fotovoltaica. Generación distribuida conectada a red</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2018</year>
      </dates>
      <abstract>En los últimos años las Energías Renovables (ER) han tenido un progresivo protagonismo en la generación de electricidad en diversas partes del mundo, el cual ha sido motivado esencialmente por la creciente conciencia sobre la irreversibilidad del cambio climático producido por las emisiones de gases de efecto invernadero por la combustión de combustibles fósiles. Entre las tecnologías de generación mediante fuentes renovables, la Energía Solar Fotovoltaica (FV) se destaca a nivel global por su rápido crecimiento, como consecuencia de las políticas de promoción de algunos estados nacionales y su abaratamiento producto de la economía de escala, en un marco de continuo crecimiento tarifario en el sector eléctrico que vuelve aún más competitiva su implementación. En el presente artículo se pasa revista al estado actual del desarrollo de la energía solar FV en el contexto de las ER, tanto a nivel global como local, se consideran las estrategias de generación centralizada y distribuida y, asimismo, se comentan los proyectos desarrollados por la CNEA para la instalación de sistemas piloto conectados a la red para la generación distribuida. Finalmente, se resumen los distintos modelos tarifarios, así como los aspectos legales y normativos vigentes en el país. In recent years, Renewable Energies (RE) have had a progressive role in the electricity generation around the world, motivated essentially on an increasing awareness about the irreversibility of climate change produced by greenhouse gas emissions associated with the burning of fossil fuels. Among renewable generation technologies, Photovoltaic Solar Energy (PV) emerges at global level due to its rapid growth, as a consequence of promotion of national policies in several countries as well as the continuous reduction of costs in PV industry due to scale economy, within the framework of increasingly tariffs in the electricity sector that make PV implementation even more competitive. In this article, the state of the art of PV development in the frame of the RE, at global and local level, is reviewed, strategies of centralized and distributed generation are considered, and also projects developed by CNEA for grid connected pilot systems installation for distributed generation are presented. Finally, the different tariff models are reviewed, as well as the legal and regulation aspects applicable in the country.</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Ciencia e Investigación</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Velasco Muñoz, Álvaro
          </author>
          <author>
            Calvache, Óscar Salazar
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Evolución De La Generación De Energía Solar Fotovoltaica En Colombia</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2019</year>
      </dates>
      <abstract>Resumen En Colombia se habla de uno de los reglones más importantes de la economía nacional en todos los escenarios; medios de comunicación, programas de gobierno, organizaciones gubernamentales, organizaciones no gubernamentales, la academia, inversionistas locales y extranjeros, entre otros; y sucede porque la energía es un factor determinante en cada uno de estos sectores sociales y económicos del país y no podría ser de otra manera porque Colombia es un país muy rico en recursos naturales lo que le ha permitido contar con importantes fuentes de generación de energía eléctrica , a través de termoeléctricas e hidroeléctricas, y hoy puede estar a la vanguardia de los países del continente en generación de energía a través de fuentes no convencionales, como lo son las energías limpias renovables, que aunque es una política de interés nacional relativamente nueva, se está avanzando rápidamente en su implementación, por lo cual es importante destacar la energía solar fotovoltaica, como una de las más impacto social y económico, por su facilidad de implementación y cobertura, en toda la geografía nacional colombiana, también es importante resaltar su evolución científica, técnica, jurídica y económica. Palabras clave: generación de energía, energía solar fotovoltaica, impacto socioambiental. Abstract In Colombia, there is talk of one of the most important registers of the national economy in all scenarios, media, government programs, governmental organizations, non-governmental organizations, academia, local investors and foreigners, among others, and it happens because energy is a determining factor in each of these social and economic sectors of the country, and it could not be otherwise because Colombia is a country very rich in natural resources, which has allowed it to have important sources of electricity generation, through thermoelectric s and hydroelectric plants, and today can be at the forefront of the countries of the continent in generating energy through unconventional sources, such as renewable clean energy, which although it is a relatively new policy of national interest, rapid progress is being made in its implementation, so it is important to highlight photovoltaic solar energy, as one of the most social and economic impact, for its ease of implementation and coverage, throughout Colombia&#39;s national geography, it is also important to highlight its scientific, technical, legal and economic developments.</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Repositorio Institucional USC</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
    <record>
      <ref-type name="Journal Article"></ref-type>
      <contributors>
        <authors>
          <author>
            Pérez, J.
          </author>
          <author>
            Vargas, C.
          </author>
          <author>
            Riaño, D.
          </author>
        </authors>
        <secondary-authors>
        </secondary-authors>
      </contributors>
      <titles>
        <title>Colombia towards an electricity generation matrix using renewable energies</title>
      </titles>
      <dates>
        <year>2019</year>
      </dates>
      <volume>17</volume>
      <electronic-resource-num>10.24084&#x2F;repqj17.272</electronic-resource-num>
      <abstract>The purpose of this paper is present a review about to the currently legislation in Colombia with respect to renewable energies. The mainly goals are: (i) to explain the energy policy regulation related to renewables energy; and (ii) to characterize using descriptive statistics renewables projects based on wind, small hydro and photovoltaic. In addition, the analyses allow to understand the existing potential in the different regions of the country. This information was collected through of the procedures developed by UPME and CREG agencies in Colombia.</abstract>
      <periodical><full-title>Renewable Energy and Power Quality Journal</full-title></periodical>
      <keywords>
      </keywords>
      <urls>
        <related-urls>
        </related-urls>
      </urls>
    </record>
  </records>
</xml>